D. KAVITHA (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Programming, Technical Architecture, Web Development, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL



Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 3 Month(s) Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Programming, Technical Architecture, Web

Development, HTML, CSS, Javascript, SQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Having 4+ Years of Experience with AGILE SCRUM Methodology involvement in some of phases in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) such as design, implementation and maintenance of Web Based and Client-Server.

Technical expertise in Microsoft Technologies, such as C#,.NET Framework(4.0/4.5), ASP.NET Web Forms, MVC, Visual

Experience in client side development using HTML, javaScript, Jqueryand CSS.

Expertise knowledge on Object Oriented Programming (OOPS) Concepts including Inheritance, Abstraction, Encapsulation and Polymorphism.

Experience in writing database objects (Stored Procedures, Views and Functions).

Worked extensively with ADO.NET objects such as Data Adapter, Dataset, and Data Reader to interact with databases like SQL Server 2017.

Good experience in Entity framework

Good experience in Exception Handling.

Experience in Asp.net MVC 5.0.

Experience in Angular 5.0 and Web API

Knowledge on Microsoft Azure, Vue JS

Work Experience

Sesat Solutions as Software Engineer Feb 2018 to Nov 2020

L&T Technologies as Software Engineer

Apr 2017 to Dec 2017

EESoft technologies as Software Engineer

Aug 2016 to Jul 2017

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from JNTU College of Engineering, Hyderabad in 2015

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Windows 10, XP		
C#.Net (4.5/4.0)		
ASP.NET (4.5/4.0), JavaScript		
jQuery, ASP.NET MVC		
Angular 5.0, Web API, Entity FrameWork		
HTML, Css.		
Visual Studio 2017		
sql server management studio		
.NET Framework 4.5/4.0		
MS SQL Server 2012		
ADO.NET 4.0/3.5		
MS SQLServer 2017/Microsoft IIS(7.0/6.0)		

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time